# Gift Alabo Thomson

Software Engineer

### Contact

- **□** +2348165940838
- ≥ alabo.gift93@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/alabo-gift-b60baa170
- github.com/AlaboGift

## Technical Skills

Web Security

Very Good

Search Engine Optimization

Excellent

Testing and maintenance

Excellent

Algorithm Implementation

Excellent

## **DevOps**

Heroku, Git, AWS S3, React Dev Tools, Redux Dev tools, SSH, Unit testing, Intergration testing

#### Front End

React, Redux, Bootstrap, Webpack, Babel, CSS3, HTML5, Javascript, Jquery Performance-driven and motivated Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of extensive experience as Full Stack web developer with solid understanding of front - end technologies, MVC frameworks, Restful web services and Data Base designing. Proven history of developing useful, efficient and cost-effective projects as well as a complex problem-solver with analytical and driven mindset.

Expertise in using React.js/Redux to build User Interface, strong knowledge of state store, middleware, action creator, reducer and container.

# Work History

## White Creativity

Job Title: Software Engineer and Instructor

Duration: Sep 2020 - Current

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed a full-stack web applications, using React that allows users to create and manage their resume, proposals, invoices and receipts. User's details is stored on a back-end created using PHP and MySQL.
- Developed a School Management Application using React, Laravel and MySQL.
- Used HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and jQuery to build Interactive User Interface (UI), created responsive web pages using react bootstrap framework.
- Worked on Lifecycle Methods, State, Props, and Events to create interactive and stateful React Components, achieved routing using react-router.
- Created class based and function based components, added necessary event listeners.
- Used Git for version Control and Repository
- Used Heroku for DevOps

## Akyegroup Ltd.

Job Title: Web Developer

Duration: Mar 2020 - Sep 2020

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed an E-Commerce and Service Delivery Application where users can also swap old, used items for new items, it was built using React, Laravel and MySQL.
- Implemented communication strategies between React

### **Back End**

PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, AJAX

# Operating System

Windows, Linux

## Soft Skills

Collaboration
Communication
Critical Thinking
Problem Solving
Adaptability

## Languages

English (Fluent)

Components.

- Designed rich featured action creators and corresponding reducers.
- Adopted MySQL for data storage, designed different schemas and data access services to communicate with MySQL.
- Used Laravel to build server side logic, and handle http requests.
- Used Git for version Control and Repository
- Used Heroku for DevOps

#### **Spatrum Creative Agency**

Job Title: Web Developer

Duration: Sep 2017 - Feb 2019

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Involved in requirements analysis, understand the requirements of each technical part.
- Actively participated in meetings with clients to determine website goals and development strategies.
- Developed a Multi Vendor E-Commerce Application, it was built using Codeigniter and MySQL.
- Developed a School Management Application using Codeigniter and MySQL.
- Used Git for version Control and Repository

#### White Creativity

Job Title: Intern

Duration: Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

- Was taught Web Development, Version Control Using Git and graphics design.
- Delivered clerical support by handling range of routine and special requirements.
- Helped with administrative support, including managing incoming calls, coordinating files and sorting mail.
- Achieved management recognition by designing and implementing special project during internship.
- Contributed to content creation for company website.
- Worked on projects using knowledge gained in classes to put together recommendations for issues.
- Sorted and organized files, spreadsheets and reports.
   Interacted with customers by phone, email or in-person to provide information.

## Education

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Science (BSC), Computer

Science

Rivers State University - Rivers State, Nigeria

# **Projects**

#### Online Learning Platform

Developed an eLearning school ERP system using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Mysql DB and PHP Codelgniter framework. https://www.learnstressfree.com

#### eFashion Store

Ecommerce platform for buying fashion apparels, built using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Mysql DB and PHP Laravel framework. <a href="https://themobileshop.com.ng">https://themobileshop.com.ng</a>

### **School Management Application**

Platform for management of students, staff and results built using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Mysql DB and PHP Laravel framework. <a href="https://school.whitecreativity.com">https://school.whitecreativity.com</a>

#### **Switdocs**

Application that allows users to create and manage their resume, proposals, invoices and receipts. User's details is stored on a back-end created using PHP and MySQL. https://switdocs.whitecreativity.com

#### Gubdjournals

An eJournal Website, Journals and article details is stored on a back-end created using PHP and MySQL.

https://gubdjournals.org

# **Affiliations**

- Facebook Developers Circle, Lagos
- Facebook Developers Circle, Gombe
- Nigerian Association of Computer Science Students

# Certifications

2019-06	Certified in PHP
2019-07	Certified in JavaScript
2019-08	Certified in MySQL
2020-06	NYSC Discharge Certificate